We were in a store and a guy in that store...
...told us to put our uniforms on.
"What the hell are you talking about?"
He says. "The USA is in a war with Japan."
We couldn't believe it.
Well. our country was attacked.
It's different.
It wasn't like Korea or Vietnam.
We were attacked.
And. you know. it was a feeling that...
...maybe. we're just dumb country people
but...
...where I come from a lot of us volunteered.
"Who would like to volunteer for the Tank
Corps?
"Who would like to volunteer for the Air
Force?
"Who would like to volunteer for the Navy?" or
whatever.
And then. they said:
"Who would like to volunteer for the
Airborne?"
Somebody says. "What the hell's the Airborne?"
Nobody ever heard of it.
We came from a small. small town.
And three fellows in that town that were 4F...
...committed suicide because they couldn't go.
A different time.
I did things.
I didn't do them for medals.
I didn't do them for accolades. I did 'em
because it's what had to be done.
The guy says. "would you jump out of
airplanes?
"You know. you got all your army equipment...
"...and you jump out of airplanes. to fight
the enemy."
These guys. they said. "Go to hell."
Nobody put up their hands.
And then. I don't know what it was brought it
up...
...but the guy giving the speech was saying:
"But you get paid $50 a month more."
So. that made it a hundred bucks.
Do you want subtitles for any video?
-=[ ai.OpenSubtitles.com ]=-
I want a whiff of chicken pie.
Okay. boys. let's get this gear stowed.
Fox Company...we go in five.
"In the name of the Father..."
1st Platoon. draw small arms.
Do you need a hand. Lieutenant?
Easy Company! Listen up!
Gather up around me.
Just move it up. Come on. gentlemen.
Let's go!
Now. the Channel coast is socked in with rain
and fog.
High winds on the drop zone.
No jump tonight.
The invasion has been postponed.
We're on a 24-hour stand-down. Son of a bitch.
Drill sergeants. take charge.
Well. this is quite a surprise.
Not particularly.
It so happens I rather expected it.
Well. I can't see how you people can pass up
$80.000 for the Cause
For whose cause?
If you're so interested in serving a cause...
...why don't you join the Army?
I think it's clearing up.
You think it's clearing up?
No.
I think it's clearing up.
How are your men?
They'll be fine.
5:00 in New York.
4:00 in Chicago.
Happy hour. huh?
Yeah.
Happy hour.
A couple of drinks.
Maybe an early dinner before the theater.
A civilized place for civilized men.
Should've been born earlier. Nix.
What. and give up all this?
We'll go to Chicago. I'll take you there.
Yeah.
We'll see.
Actually. you know who's from there?
Who? Oh. him.
712 days of that son of a bitch and here we
are.
You people are at the position of attention.
Private Perconte. have you been blousing your
trousers over your boots like a paratrooper?
No. sir.
Then explain the creases at the bottom.
No excuse. sir.
Volunteering for the Parachute Infantry is one
thing...
...but you've got a long way to prove you
belong here.
Your weekend pass is revoked.
Name? Luz. George.
Dirt in the rear side aperture.
Pass revoked.
When did you sew on these chevrons. Sergeant
Lipton?
Yesterday. sir.
Long enough to notice this. Revoked.
Sir.
Name?
Malarkey. Donald G.
Malarkey's slang for bullshit. isn't it?
Yes. sir.
Rust on the butt plate hinge spring. Private
Bullshit.
Revoked.
Name?
Liebgott. Joseph D.. sir.
Rusty bayonet. Liebgott.
You want to kill Germans?
Yes. sir.
Not with this.
I wouldn't take this rusty piece of shit to
war.
And I will not take you to war in your
condition.
Now. thanks to these men and their
infractions...
...every man in the company who had a weekend
pass...
...has lost it.
Change into your PT gear. we're running
Currahee.
2nd Platoon. fall out.
We have two minutes.
Fall out!
I ain't going up that hill.
Perconte. what are you thinking of blousing
your pants?
Shut up. okay?
He gigged everyone.
You should know better.
Don't give him no excuses.
Excuses?
Why don't you come here. look at these
trousers...
...get down and tell me if there's a crease?
Let's go on the road in PT formation.
Let's move. move. move!
Perconte. let's go. Perconte.
Private White. why are you not in your PT
gear?
I asked you a question. Private.
Oh. Easy Company.
While you're running. don't worry.
We'll take your dames to the movies.
Yeah. good. they need some female company.
Where do we run?
Currahee.
What does "Currahee" mean?
We stand alone.
How far up. how far down?
Three miles up. three miles down.
And what company is this?
Easy Company.
And what do we do? Stand alone.
Do not help that man! Do not help that man!
We do not stop.
You've got 30 minutes to get to the top of
this mountain...
...if you want to serve in the Paratroopers.
Hi-ho. Silver!
You can make it up there.
Come on.
Come on. Alley. let's go.
Come on. Guarnere.
Christenson. come on.
I never thought I'd see the day. Private Wynn.
We are coming on 23 minutes.
That may be good enough for the rest of the
506...
...but that is not good enough for Easy
Company.
We can make it. we can do this. come on.
I'm going to say something.
To who?
Lieutenant Winters.
What is it?
Permission to speak. sir?
Permission granted.
Sir. we got nine companies. sir.
That we do.
How come we're the only company...
...marching every Friday night. 12 miles. full
pack in the pitch dark?
Why do you think. Private Randleman?
Lieutenant Sobel hates us. sir.
Lieutenant Sobel does not hate
Easy Company. Private Randleman.
He just hates you.
Thank you. sir.
He hates him back.
He hates you. too. Muck.
Lieutenant Winters. I want canteens out of
belts with the caps unscrewed.
Easy Company. canteens out and open.
On my command. they will pour the contents
onto the ground.
On the CO's order. you will upend your
canteen.
Now. Lieutenant.
Pour them.
Who is this?
Christenson.
Why is there no water in your canteen?
You drank from your canteen. didn't you?
Lieutenant.
Yes. sir.
Was this man ordered to not drink from his
canteen during the Friday night march?
He was. sir.
Private Christenson. you have disobeyed a
direct order.
You will fill your canteen...
...and repeat all 12 miles of the march
immediately.
Yes. sir.
Fall out!
What in the name of God are you doing with my
company?
You're late and you allow troopers to disobey
direct orders?
No excuse. sir.
You're making me look bad. Lieutenant.
This is not Dog Company. This is not Fox
Company.
This is Easy Company.
Under my command. this will be the first...
...and finest company in this regiment.
I want the names of six men.
Their infractions and your disciplinary
recommendations on my desk by 0130.
Is that clear?
What infractions. sir?
Find some.
So. what'd you do?
Picked six men and gave them latrine duty.
The lucky six?
McDowell. Toye. Perconte.
Lipton. Muck and Guarnere.
Why them?
It was their turn.
Sobel's a genius.
I had a headmaster just like him in prep
school.
I know the type.
Lewis.
Michelangelo's a genius. Beethoven's a genius.
You know a man in this company who wouldn't
double-time Currahee with a full pack...
...just to piss in that guy's morning coffee?
Let's go. let's go.
Stand in the door.
1.000
. 2.000.
You just broke both your legs. Private Gordon.
Are you trying to get killed?
No. sir.
Stand in the door.
Shit.
To the wall.
Over as a team.
Go on. against the wall.
Jesus. what the hell is this?
That's pig guts. boy.
Goddamn it!
Why are you here. Private Gordon?
To be in the Airborne. sir.
I don't believe you. Why are you here. Private
Gordon?
To be in the Airborne. sir.
You have 50 minutes to the top and back. and I
will be watching you.
What are you waiting for?
Easy Company has the finest performance record
in the entire 2nd Battalion.
I believe every bit of that is thanks to you.
Congratulations. Captain Sobel.
Thank you. sir.
Isn't that Lieutenant Winters leading Easy
Company in PT?
Yes. sir.
He's a damned good man.
I was planning on giving him a set of these
today.
Why don't you do it? He'd be proud to get them
from you.
Pornography. contraband.
Non-regulation clothing. contraband.
This man had 200 prophylactic kits in his
footlocker.
How in the name of God was he going to have
the strength to fight the war?
How is it Private Tipper...
...has spare time for so much correspondence?
Captain. are personal letters to be considered
contraband?
These men aren't paratroopers yet. Lieutenant.
They have no personal property.
What is this?
Anybody?
It's a can of peaches. sir.
Lieutenant Nixon thinks this is a can of
peaches.
That is incorrect. Lieutenant.
Your weekend pass is cancelled.
This is United States Army property...
...which was taken. without authorization.
from my mess facility...
...and I will not tolerate thievery in my
unit.
Whose footlocker is this?
Private Parks. sir.
Get rid of him.
All weekend passes are cancelled.
Officers included.
Carry on.
Lieutenant Winters.
Colonel Sink has seen fit to promote you.
As First Lieutenant. you'll serve as my
executive officer.
Congratulations.
Thank you. sir.
And. as a test of your organizational skills
and command potential...
...I am designating you mess officer for 14
days.
Report to the mess kitchen at 0515 hours.
Company breakfast to be served at 0600.
Yes. sir.
And. Dick. there's rain forecast tomorrow...
...so the company will have a light afternoon
of lecture and classroom instruction.
I think a special meal before their afternoon
off...
...would be a welcome change of pace.
Would you agree?
Yes. sir.
I like spaghetti.
Hold on. more coming.
These guys are packing it away.
This stuff is orange.
Spaghetti ain't supposed to be orange.
This ain't spaghetti.
This is army noodles with ketchup.
You ain't got to eat it.
Oh. come on. Gonorrhea. as a fellow Italian...
...you know that calling this spaghetti is a
mortal sin.
I'll have it. No. I'm eating here.
Hey. get out of here.
Orders changed. get up!
Lectures are cancelled.
Easy Company is running up Currahee.
Move. move!
Three miles up. three miles down.
Hi-ho. Silver!
Let's go. let's go.
You're a washout. Private Hoobler!
You should pack up both your ears and go home.
Looks like Gordon's done.
Aren't you. Gordon. You finished?
You do not deserve to get your wings.
Private Randleman. you look tired.
There's an ambulance waiting for you at the
bottom of the hill.
It can all be over right now.
No more pain. no more Currahee.
No more Captain Sobel.
"We pull upon the risers We fall upon the
grass
"We never land upon our feet We always hit our
ass
"Hide tidee. Christ almighty Who the hell are
we?
"Zim zam. goddamn! We're Airborne Infantry
"We pull upon the risers We fall upon the
grass
"We never land upon our feet We always hit our
ass
"Hide tidee. Christ almighty Who the hell are
we?
"Zim zam. goddamn! We're Airborne Infantry"
So. do we feel like we're ready to be army
paratroopers?
Yes. Sergeant.
I hope so.
This'll be the first of five exits from a C-47
aircraft scheduled for today.
Get ready!
Stand up!
Hook up!
Upon successful completion of your fifth and
final jump...
...you'll be certified army paratroopers.
Check equipment!
Sound off for equipment check!
Nine okay.
Eight okay.
Seven okay.
Six okay.
Five okay.
Four okay.
Three okay.
Two okay.
One okay.
There'll be a lot of men dropping from the sky
today.
Hopefully. under deployed canopies.
Stand in the door!
I guarantee you're going to love it.
Lieutenant.
Go. go!
Jumping from 1.000 feet AGL...
...in sticks of 12 jumpers per aircraft.
All you have to do is remember what you were
taught...
...and I guarantee you. gravity will take care
of the rest.
Go. go. go. go!
Go. go. go!
Damn it.
And. gentlemen. rest assured...
...any refusals in the aircraft or at the
door...
...and I guarantee you. you will be out of the
Airborne.
Four okay.
Three okay.
Two okay.
One okay.
Stand in the door.
Go!
1.000. 2.000. 3.000.
4.000. 5.000. 6.000 ...
...7.000. 8.000. 9.000!
Hi-ho. Silver!
Now just think. if you had any class or style
like me...
...somebody might mistake you for somebody.
You mean like your fucking sergeant?
I'm just kidding.
Congratulations. Martin.
Corporal Toye. there will be no leaning in my
company.
Are those dusty jump wings?
How do you expect to slay the Huns with dust
on your jump wings?
Luz. just give me a drink.
Hell of an idea. Joe.
There you go.
Three miles up. three miles down.
Ten-hut!
Well. at ease. paratroopers.
Good evening. Easy Company.
Evening. sir.
Now. Parachute Infantry is a brand-new
concept...
...in American military history.
But. by God. the 506 is going to forge that
brand-new concept...
...into victory.
Yes. sir.
I want you to know that I'm damned proud of
each and every one of you.
Now. you deserve this party.
Thank you. Sergeant Grant.
Sir.
So. I want you to have fun and remember our
motto:
Currahee!
Petty.
Map.
Come on.
Ah. Christ.
We're in the wrong position.
We're textbook position for ambush. sir.
We should sit tight. let the enemy team come
into our killing zone.
They're right out there somewhere.
Let's just get them.
Sir. we have perfect cover here.
Lieutenant. deploy your troops.
2nd Platoon. move out.
What?
Tactical column.
Captain. you've just been killed. along with
95 percent of your company.
Your outfit?
Easy Company. 2nd Battalion. 506th.
Leave three wounded men on the ground and
report back to the assembly area.
Goddamn it.
You. you. you.
Well. what are you going to do?
Nothing. just keep training the men.
Am I interrupting?
No. no.
Lieutenant Lewis Nixon.
Lieutenant Harry Welsh. just in from the 82nd.
Congratulations on the promotion.
Thanks. if you want to call it that.
You'll learn him pretty quickly.
No flaws. no vices. no sense of humor.
Just like your chums up at battalion staff.
What's up?
I'm hearing a lot of rumblings.
Sobel?
Just talking about that.
So. he gets a little jumpy in the field?
He gets jumpy and then you get killed.
That's nice.
Yeah. listen. if we discuss it. I think it
should just be amongst ourselves.
Absolutely.
2nd Platoon. ready?
Ready. sir.
Then get them in formation.
We're moving out.
Yes. sir.
Shut up. Cobb.
You got to admit it.
He's got no chance.
Either the Krauts will get him or one of us.
Who. Sobel?
He screwed up one maneuver.
Well. you know. I'm always fumbling with
grenades.
It would be easy if one went off by accident.
you know?
Well. now they must have put him in charge for
a reason.
Yeah. 'cause the Army wouldn't make a mistake.
right?
Going my way? Wherever the train takes me.
Where do you suppose that might be? I haven't
got a clue.
Yeah. come on. take a guess.
Atlantic. Pacific. Atlantic?
I'm not the intelligence officer.
Well. as such. I. of course. know. but if I
told you. I'd have to kill you.
So. don't tell me.
New York City.
Troopship.
England.
We're invading Europe. my friend.
Fortress Europa.
Since when do I drink?
If I thought you'd drink it. I wouldn't offer
it to you.
Nix?
What are you going to do when you get into
combat?
I have every confidence in my scrounging
abilities.
And I have a case of VAT 69 hidden in your
footlocker.
Really?
Oh. yeah.
'Morning.
This could turn into a real nice trip.
"Dear sir or madam:
"Soon your son will drop from the sky to
engage and defeat the enemy.
"Your frequent letters of love and
encouragement...
"...will arm him with a fighting heart.
"With that he cannot fail. but will win glory
for himself...
"...make you proud of him. and his country
ever grateful...
"...for his service in its hour of need.
"Signed. Herbert M. Sobel. Captain
Commanding."
Right now. some lucky bastard's
headed for the South Pacific.
Oh. what I'd give.
He's going to get billeted on some tropical
island.
Keep talking.
Sitting under a palm tree with six naked
native girls...
...helping him cut up coconuts so he can hand-
feed them to the flamingos.
Flamingos are mean.
They bite.
So do the naked native girls.
With any luck.
Hey. guys. I'm glad I'm going to Europe.
Hitler gets one of these right across the
windpipe.
Roosevelt changes Thanksgiving to Joe Toye
Day...
...and pays me $10.000 a year for the rest of
my fucking life.
What if we don't get to Europe?
What if they send us to North Africa?
My brother's in North Africa.
He says it's hot.
Really. it's hot in Africa?
Shut up.
The point is. it don't matter where we go.
In combat. the only person you can trust...
...is yourself and the fellow next to you.
Hey. as long as he's a paratrooper.
Oh. yeah?
And what if that paratrooper turns out to be
Sobel?
If I'm next to Sobel in combat. I'm moving on
down the line.
Hook up with some other officer. like Heyliger
or Winters.
I like Winters. he's a good man.
But when the bullets start flying...
...I don't know if I want a Quaker doing my
fighting for me.
How do you know he's a Quaker?
He ain't Catholic.
Neither is Sobel.
That prick's a son of Abraham.
He's what?
He's a Jew.
I'm a Jew.
Congratulations.
Get your nose out of my face.
What's all that about?
Gonorrhea called Sobel a Jew.
Liebgott took offense 'cause he's a Jew too.
Fighting over Sobel. that's smart.
Attack!
No. you want to kill him!
Parry right. parry left.
Thrust!
Take cover.
Okay.
Yesterday. we talked about magnetic
declination...
...and the "left add. right subtract" rule.
Today we're putting it into practice.
There are two basic types of fighting
positions.
The first is the prepared position.
The advantages of a prepared position are that
it gives you cover and concealment.
Commence fire!
We'll then maneuver right in through these
trees.
At the same time. our second platoon. in this
particular case. moves over here.
He's then going to close with and kill or
capture that German.
Sobel's late.
Why is there a fence here?
There should be no fence here.
Give me the map.
Perconte. Luz.
Get the men. get them...
Take cover behind those trees.
You heard the word. Let's go over there.
There should be no... There should be no fence
here.
We could go over it. sir.
Really?
That's not the point. Where the goddamn...
Where the goddamn hell are we?
Perconte?
Yeah.
Sobel's lost again. right? Yeah. he's lost.
Fucking Christ.
Can you do Major Horton?
Does a wild bear crap in the woods. son?
Maybe the good major can goose this schmuck.
Get us moving?
No way.
Yes. You got to.
All right. just this once.
Three-five-six-eight-three-three.
Isn't that the intersection?
No. sir. it's here.
You're a full grid off.
Goddamn it.
Is there a problem. Captain Sobel?
Who said that?
Who broke silence?
I think it's Major Horton. sir.
Major Horton?
What is he... Did he join us?
I think maybe he's moving between the
platoons. sir.
What is the goddamn holdup. Mr. Sobel?
A fence. sir.
God!
A barbed wire fence.
Oh. that dog just ain't going to hunt!
Now. you cut that fence and get this goddamn
platoon on the move!
Yes. sir!
Where are my goddamn wire cutters?
We have to move.
Sir. without Captain Sobel and 1st Platoon?
It's a T-intersection. We improvise.
Double envelopment laid on a base of fire to
cut the road in all directions.
Hook right with first squad. Tell Guarnere to
move left with second.
I'll be right up the middle with third. go.
Yes. sir.
Deary me.
Bloody hell.
You've done it now. Yanks.
You've captured me.
Hi-ho. Silver!
Would that be the enemy?
As a matter of fact. yes.
Good work. 2nd Platoon.
We took the objective.
Who is the idiot who cut that man's fence?
I was ordered to. sir.
By whom?
Major Horton. sir.
Major Horton? Yes. sir.
Major Horton told you to do that? Yes. sir.
Major Horton ordered you to cut the fence?
Yes. he did.
Major Horton is on leave in London.
Get those cows out of here.
Lieutenant Winters.
With Captain Sobel's compliments. sir.
Lieutenant.
Oh. for crying out loud.
This spells court-martial.
Wide open! Yes.
No. sir. I do not understand.
Your orders to me were to inspect the latrines
at 1000 hours.
From 0930 to 0955 I was censoring the enlisted
men's mail by order of Colonel Strayer.
At 1000 hours I followed your orders to the
minute.
I changed that time to 0945.
No one told me. sir.
I telephoned.
I'm quartered with a family that has no
telephone.
And sent a runner.
No runner found me. Captain.
Irregardless. when given a task
to perform by a ranking officer you
Should have delegated your task
of latrine inspection to another officer.
You failed to do so.
Were I to let such a failure of duty by my own
X O go unpunished...
...what kind of message is that to the men?
I performed my duty as I was ordered. sir.
And I disagree.
So. your options are quite simple. Lieutenant.
Punishment for your offenses will be denial of
a 48-hour pass for 60 days.
Stand before me at attention.
Or you may initiate a letter of appeal and
request a trial by court-martial.
You spend your weekends on the base anyway.
Dick.
Be a man. take the punishment.
May I borrow your pen. sir?
My endorsement. sir.
I request trial by court-martial.
We lost Winters to battalion mess.
You're shitting me. No.
Strayer did it. while they try to figure out
the procedures for his court-martial.
Nix better find a loophole and get him out.
And if he don't?
Winters scrambles eggs while the rest of us
make the big jump with Sobel.
Not me.
So we're going through with this. right?
We've got to do something.
Yeah.
All right.
Good.
But we'd all better be clear on the
consequences.
I don't care about the consequences.
We could be lined up against a wall and shot.
Now. I'm ready to face that.
And every one of us had better be. too.
I will not follow that man into combat.
Me neither.
All right.
Then let's do it.
"I hereby...
"...no longer wish to serve...
"...as a non-commissioned officer...
"...in Easy Company."
All right. boys.
Good luck.
I ought to have you all shot!
This is nothing less than an act of mutiny...
...while we prepare for the goddamn invasion
of Europe.
Sergeant Harris.
Sir.
Turn in your stripes. collect your gear.
You are hereby transferred out of my regiment.
Sir.
Get out.
Sergeant Ranney.
Sir.
You consider yourself lucky. I'm only busting
you to private.
All of you NCOs have disgraced the 101st
Airborne.
Consider yourself lucky that we are on the eve
of the largest action in the history of warfare...
...which leaves me no choice but to spare your
lives.
Now. get out of my office and get out of my
sight.
Get.
Keep them coming. atta-boy.
I can only speculate. sir. Most of the men
would never do this...
...but I believe just a few of the sergeants
may have felt...
...their loyalty lay more to the platoon than
to the company.
And these few sergeants convinced all of the
other NCOs in your company...
...to turn in their stripes?
As staff sergeants. they have a great amount
of influence. sir.
But as I say. the rest are good men.
I know them. I can work with them.
This business with the Winters' court-
martial...
...has been an unpleasant distraction.
Indeed it has. sir.
However...
...your command of Easy Company has been
exemplary.
Thank you. sir.
In fact. except for the actions of a few of
your non-coms...
...I believe you've fielded one of the finest
companies of soldiers I've ever seen.
Yes. sir.
Herbert. Division has established...
...a parachute training school at Chilton
Foliat.
The idea is for non-infantry types who...
...were vital to the coming invasion...
...such as doctors and chaplains. to take jump
training there.
I can't think of anyone more qualified...
...to command such a school than you are.
Sir?
I'm reassigning you to Chilton Foliat.
I'm losing Easy Company?
The war effort needs you elsewhere.
Permission to speak. sir?
Granted.
Is... Who will be replacing me?
Lieutenant Meehan from Baker Company is
senior.
Good luck at Chilton Foliat. Herbert.
Don't let us down now.
No. sir.
Carry on.
2nd Platoon. listen up.
I want the first squad and A-side tents right
up there.
Third squad. second row...
Holy shit.
No. it's all right. We're tommies...
...not bleeding boche.
Is all this real?
Yeah. yeah.
Some is from the Hermans. somebody's tailor's
knocked up.
For you. so you can get your mince pies on
this Jerry clobber...
...if you know what I mean.
Not really.
Mack. you got a Luger?
I'm dying to get a real Luger.
Yeah. go on then.
A quick butchers. yeah?
Boy. she sure is a doozy.
Yeah. it's pukka. ain't it?
What?
Hey. Petty.
Hey. mate.
You're having a bath if you think you're half-
inching that.
Oh. yeah.
Sorry. Well. good luck.
You too. mate.
What's up. Hoobs?
These men have been through the toughest
training the Army has to offer.
Under the worst possible circumstances.
And they volunteered for it.
Christ. I was just shooting craps with them.
It's not like...
You know why they volunteered?
So. when things got really bad. the man next
to them would be the best.
Not some draftee who's going to get him
killed.
Are you ticked because they like me?
Because I'm spending time to get to know my
soldiers?
You've been with these guys for what. two
years?
I've been here for six days.
You're gambling. Bob.
So what? Soldiers do that.
I don't deserve a reprimand for it.
What if you'd won?
What? What if you'd won?
Never put yourself in a position where you can
take from these men.
Lieutenant Meehan?
Enter.
On the last training jump. I had a compass.
Close the flap.
Then we turn left.
Yeah.
Bearing zero-four-two.
12 minutes.
Then another left?
Call it three-five-eight...
...for 10 and a half minutes.
Green light. right over Ramsbury.
Ramsbury.
Every single time.
Linear distance on the grid of about...
Okay.
Ramsbury.
Upottery.
So
...
It's Normandy.
St. Marie du Mont.
Causeway Number One.
Causeway Number Two.
The ultimate field problem.
The estuary of the Douve River divides two
beachheads...
...code-named Utah. here. and Omaha. here.
Seaborne Infantry will hit these beaches in
force...
...at a date and time to be specified.
H-hour. D-day.
Airborne's objective. gentlemen. is to take
the town of Carentan...
...thus linking Utah and Omaha into a single.
continuous beachhead.
...linking Omaha and Utah into one continuous
beachhead.
Each trooper will learn this operation by
heart...
...and know his and every other outfits'
mission to the detail.
Meehan?
Yes. Dukeman.
Sir. are we dropping tonight?
When it's time for you to know. we'll let you
know.
In the meantime. study these sand tables.
maps. and reconnaissance photos...
...until you can draw a map of the area by
memory.
Now. we will drop behind this Atlantic wall
five hours before the 4th Infantry lands at Utah.
And between our assembly area and the
battalion's objective...
...there is a German garrison right here in
this area. St. Marie du Mont.
Easy Company will destroy that garrison.
Three-day supply of K rations. chocolate bars.
charms. candy...
...powdered coffee. sugar. and matches.
Compass. bayonet. entrenching tool.
ammunition. gas mask.
Musette bag with ammo. my webbing. my.45.
canteen...
...two cartons of smokes.
Hawkins mine. two grenades.
smoke grenade. gamma grenade...
...TNT. this bullshit. and a pair of nasty
skivvies.
What's your point?
This weighs as much as I do.
I've still got my chute. my reserve chute. my
Mae West. my M-1.
Where are you keeping your brass knuckles?
I could use some brass knuckles.
Hey. anything for me?
Sergeant Martin.
For Talbert.
Heavy! condoms?
I don't know. probably.
What you got?
"Dear Floyd: Give them hell."
It's from the chief of the Kokomo Police.
Right.
You've got to love cops.
All right. listen up. listen up.
If you did not sign your GI life insurance
policy...
...you go on over and see Sergeant Evans at
the headquarters company tent.
You boys don't let your families miss out on
$10.000.
You hear that. Gerry?
Hey. Lip?
Yeah. boy.
Has Guarnere said anything about his brother?
No.
I got a problem.
My wife keeps up with things back home.
casualty lists and like that.
Yeah?
Guarnere's brother in Italy?
Henry?
Killed in Monte Cassino.
Well. I'm sure he doesn't know.
Damn.
What'd you think I should do?
If it were me. I'd tell him.
Couple of hours before we jump?
I don't know.
Why are they springing these things on us now?
It's just an extra 80 pounds strapped to your
leg.
Does anybody have any idea how the hell this
thing works?
Colonel Sink.
"Soldiers of the regiment.
"Tonight is the night of nights.
"Today. as you read this...
"...you are en route to the great adventure
for which you have trained...
"...for over two years."
So. that's why they gave us ice cream.
Easy Company. listen up!
Channel coast is socked in with rain and fog.
No jump tonight.
The invasion has been postponed.
We're on a 24-hour stand-down.
Well. this is quite a surprise.
Not particularly.
It so happens I rather expected it.
Well. I can't see how you people can pass up
$80.000 for the Cause.
For whose cause?
If you're so interested in serving a cause...
...why don't you join the Army?
Next. please.
Oh. 4F.
You look 1A to me.
You don't look so bad yourself.
"Dearest Johnny"?
Well. should you be giving blood?
I woke up.
I got the wrong goddamn jacket.
I was struck by lightning.
Nobody dancing.
It doesn't matter.
"Your pal. Bill Guarnere's brother..."
Good luck. lads.
See you. tommies.
See you. mate.
Try and get these leg straps through.
Johnny?
Got something you might be looking for.
Took your jacket by mistake.
I'm sorry.
You read it?
Where the fuck is Monte Cassino?
I don't know. Italy somewhere.
Sorry about your brother. Bill.
I'm sorry for my ma.
He was...
Let's get this over with.
Bill?
I'll meet up with you over there.
Gentlemen. Doc Roe is handing these out for
air sickness.
Orders are. "Every man takes one now. another.
30 minutes in the air."
Lieutenant.
2nd Platoon. listen up.
Good luck.
God bless you.
I'll see you in the assembly area.
If the wire contacts are sensitive. then I
think all we should have to do...
Goddamn. Lieb.
That airsick pill is making me loopy.
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm